CURRICULUM VITAE

WASEEM AKHTER

Technical Lead at HCL Tech

Contact Info:

akhterwaseem09@gmail.com

8285983654

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

6.5+ Years of extensive website development experience mainly in the area of Web application using MERN Stack Developer with React JS, Node JS, MongoDB/MYSQL, TypeScript.

Extensive experience Node JS with libraries like Sequelize, Mongoose, Type ORM, Jest, super test library.

Extensive experience React JS with libraries like Redux, React Router Dom, axios, Jest, react testing library.

Extensive experience **Next JS with TypeScript.**

Exposure to client-side scripting language, knowledge of jQuery, Ajax, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Material UI, Grommet UI, Web Page designing, JavaScript.

Extensive experience relational database like MYSQL, Maria DB, SQL Server 2008 R2, Ms Access Database, MongoDB also.

Experience in integrating various payment gateways like **Paytm**, **PayU**, **Instamojo**, **Stripe**, **Sum-up**, **Apple Pay**, **Google Pay** etc.

Working on EC2 AWS, c Panel, Plesk etc.

Worked on socket for real Web Application.

Working with Web Application.

Worked on Git, GitHub, Git Lab, Bit Bucket.

Worked on management tools like Jira, Trello etc.

Creating Rest Api using Node JS, Express JS and

Typescript.

Third Party Integration like Facebook, Google plus, Gm-ail and GitHub login etc.

Working Multiple Projects at same time.

Worked on **Jest for unit test cases**.

Working with Text **Editor** such as Sublime, Brackets, Notepad++, Visual Studio Code and IDEsuch as Adobe Dreamweaver, Net beans, Atom etc.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, Social Sanskari Pvt Ltd.

Sep 2017 to Oct 2019.

Software Developer, Neo Digi Pvt Ltd.

Nov 2019 to Nov 2020.

Software Developer, Appventurez Mobitech Pvt Ltd.

Nov 2020 to Oct 2021.

Software Developer, Tech Mahindra Pvt Ltd.

Nov 2021 to March 2023.

Technical Lead, HCL Technologies Pvt Ltd.

March 2023 to current.

EDUCATION

MCA	I.G.N.O.U
2019 - 2021	(New Delhi) (60%)
BCA	I.G.N.O.U
2015 - 2019	(New Delhi) (60%)
12thArts	C.B.S.E
2014- 2015	(Central Board Secondary Education) (80%)

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming Languages	JavaScript, Typescript, C, C++.
Framework Known	Node JS and Express JS etc.
Front-end Framework Known	React JS, Next JS, React Native, Bootstrap, CSS, Tailwind CSS.
Programming Languages and Framework	PHP, Laravel, Codelgnitor, Cake PHP.
Web Server	Apache, Xampp, Wamp, Lamp, Laragon, Mamp etc.
Databases	MYSQL, Maria DB, MS SQL SERVER 2008 R2, MongoDB.
Operating Systems	Windows 8.1, Windows 10, Windows 11, Ubuntu Linux 16.04 to Ubuntu 21.04 and Mac OS.

DETAILS OF PROJECTS

Link	www.shutterbridge.com
Role	Web Developer
Client	Romy (USA, International Project)
Team Size	10
Project Description	on

In Shutter bridge, everyone is photogenic

Let us help you find a photographer that is perfect for you. Shutter bridge was built to help connect you with a professional photographer with minimal effort on your end. You answer 4 simple questions and we do the search for you. At Shutter bridge we want you to spend as little time possible searching for a photographer to capture memories, so that you can spend more time creating new ones.

Platforms/ Environment Used	VS CODE, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React JS, Ajax,Node JS, Database MySQL.
Responsibilities	Team involved in design/development of modules. Involved in development of Reports (MySQL Database). Payment Gateway Integration with Stripe Payment Gateway.

Link	www.eyeglass.ml
Role	Web Developer
Client	For International Client
Team Size	12

Project Description

The eyeglass is dedicated to providing you with the highest standards of professional eyecare, together with a friendly service, quality products and excellent value.

As an established independent optician, we are free to select the best products from any manufacturer. This means we are able to offer you a wide choice of eyewear with quality frames. Our commitment to quality extends to the people who look after your eyesight. Atour practice your eyes will be examined by a qualified optometrist, while your spectacle or contact lenses will be provided by fully trained dispensing staff. You will always receive professional advice on your vision and on choosing the best products for your needs, appearance and lifestyle.

The eyeglass provides a comprehensive eye care service. This is reflected in the range of spectacle frames on offer. Our aim is to cater for all spectacle wearers, irrespective of age, budget or requirements. Feel free to browse at leisure through hundreds of frames on display including many of the leading designer styles.

Platforms/ Environment Used	VS CODE, Html, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery, NodeJS, React JS, Redux, Database MySQL.	
Responsibilities		
Detail Level Design analysis and Coding. Individually involved in design/development of modules. Payment Gateway Integration with Paytm etc. Involved in development of Reports My SQL Database		

Link	www.almoroojstore.com	
Role	Web Developer	
Client	Brahm Kumar Atri	
Team Size	10	

Project Description

Al Morooj has established a regional presence in the Foodservice industry, supplying to Hotels, Fine & Casual Dining restaurants, Fast Food chains and Coffee shops across the GCC market. We are growing regionally and adding more product categories to our portfolio. We have established long-term relationship with both customers and suppliers that centre on reliability and trust.

By going E-COMMERCE, the company position's, itself to become the market leader in offering online consumers a uniform and trouble-free way to search and make purchases online.

Almoroojstore.com offers a business-to-business solution with special pricing to key accounts & clients with regional presence for physical, non-perishable products. The websitealso offers a business-to-customer solution for various restaurants & hotels around gcc.

The company utilizes a consolidation approach in handling all orders that allows customers to instantly receive an accurate lead time. It also aims to save bad sales, restore customer satisfaction, stimulate repeat sales and provide an easy solution for purchase returns, while offering consumers a convenient, centralized online location to place orders.

Almoroojstore.com positions itself for rapid growth and gains a strong opportunity to raise entry barriers for possible competition.

Platforms/ Environment Used	Visual studio code, Html, css, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, React
	JS, Ajax,Node JS, Database MONGO DB.

Responsibilities

Detail Level Design analysis and Coding.

Individually involved in design/development of modules.

Involved in development of Reports MySQL Database.

Payment Gateway Integration.

Other Projects.

- www.fixitservicepros.com (in Node JS and React JS).
- www.exhibitpower2.com (in Node JS and React JS).
- www.myhelpyou.com (In Node JS and React JS).
- www.dcdc.co.in (in Node JS and React JS).
- www.cilms.com (in React JS, Node JS).
- www.treatlocally.com (React JS, Node JS, International Project).
- www.wsblog.vercel.app (in Node JS with React JS).

PERSONAL DETAILS

Father's Name: Naim Akhter
Mother's Name: Hajra Khatoon
Date of Birth: 4 Aug. 1996

Language Known: Hindi & English & Urdu

Marital Status: Married Nationality: Indian

DECLARATION

I do hereby declare that the above given details at true to the best of my knowledge and belief. All the supporting certified well is produced on demand.

Place: - DELHI

Date: - (WASEEM AKHTER)